Guide to the Jack Metcalf Papers 1973-2001
Western Washington University, Center for Pacific Northwest Studies
- Congressional Career, 1984-2001; 1995-2000; Series II
  - Washington D.C. Office files, 1984-2001; (bulk 1995-2000); Subseries 1
    - Legislative Issues, 1984-2001
      - Ground Transportation, 1995-2001
        - Everett Transportation Center, 1996-2000 (Box-folder 11/21)
        - Fare Card (Central Puget Sound), undated (Box-folder 11/22)
        - Federal Railroad Administration – Rail Safety, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 11/23)
        - High Speed Rail, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 11/24)
        - Hours of Service rules (truckers), 2000 (Box-folder 11/25)
        - Initiative 695 – Motor Vehicle Excise Tax, 1999 (Box-folder 11/26)
        - Innovative Bridge Research & Construction - funding, 1999 (Box-folder 11/27)
        - Intermodal Surface Transportation Efficiency Act (ISTEA)
          - Everett/Tacoma FAST Corridor, 1997-1998; 2000 (Box-folder 11/28)
          - FAST Corridor, 1998 (Box-folder 11/29 - 11/30)
          - Washington State project requests, 1997 (Box-folder 11/31 - 11/32)
        - Metcalf – Priority Projects, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 11/33)
        - Mount Vernon Multi-Modal Facility, 1999 (Box-folder 11/34)
        - North Sound Connecting Communities Project, 2000 (Box-folder 11/35)
        - Pacific Northwest Transportation Hearing (“Cascadia Project”), 1999 (Box-folder 11/36)
        - Rail Passenger Family Assistance Act, 1999 (Box-folder 11/37)
        - Railroad Competition and Service Improvement Act (H.R. 2784), 1999 (Box-folder 11/38 - 11/39)
        - Railroad Competition and Service Improvement Act (S. 621), 1999 (Box-folder 11/40)
        - Seattle Light Rail, 1999 (Box-folder 11/41)
        - State Route 529 – Steamboat and Ebey Slough Bridge, circa 1999 (Box-folder 11/42)
        - Subcommittee hearings – Central Puget Sound Regional Transit Authority (Sound Move Plan), 1997 (Box-folder 11/43)
        - Subcommittee hearings re: Trends in Ground Transportation, 1999 (Box-folder 11/44)
        - Tacoma Narrows Bridge Project, 1999- 2000 (Box-folder 11/45)
        - Talgo Inc., 1997-2000 (Box-folder 12/1)
        - Transportation Equity Act for the 21st Century, 1999 (Box-folder 12/2)
        - Transportation Equity Act for the 21st Century / Washington Trade Corridor, 1998 (Box-folder 12/3)
        - Transportation Equity Act: Obligations re: Indian Reservation Roads (Squaxin Island Tribe Briefing Packet), 2000 (Box-folder 12/4)
        - Transportation Labor Issues, 1999 (Box-folder 12/5)
        - Transportation Lobbyist Materials, circa 1996-2000 (Box-folder 12/6)
        - Transportation Safety, circa 1999-2000 (Box-folder 12/7)
        - Union Pacific / Southern Pacific Railroad merger, undated (Box-folder 12/8)
        - US Border – Blaine and Peace Arch Crossing Entry program, 1995 - 1999 (Box-folder 12/9)
        - US Border – Cascade Gateway Funding Applications, 1999 (Box-folder 12/10)
      - Health and Social Security, 1997-2000
        Records reflect legislative conflicts surrounding issues such as Medicare and access to prescription drugs, Drug Abuse Prevention Laws, and Patient Privacy.
        - American Association of Health Plans information (“uninsured”), 2000 (Box-folder 12/11)
        - Ambulatory Payment Classification, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 12/12)
        - Anti-Trust Legislation – Quality Health-Care Coalition Act, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 12/13 - 12/14)
        - Breaux-Thomas Proposal (Medicare), 1999 (Box-folder 12/15)
        - Clinical Laboratory Improvement Amendments program, 1999 (Box-folder 12/16)
        - Clinton Medicare Reform, 1999 (Box-folder 12/17)
        - Cost of Living Adjustments, 1999 (Box-folder 12/18)
        - Federal Lethal Drug Abuse Prevention Law (H.R. 4006), 1998 (Box-folder 12/19)
        - Federal Supplementary Medical Insurance Trust Fund – Trustees Report, 1997 (Box-folder 12/20)
        - Graduate Medical Education, 1999 (Box-folder 12/21)
        - Health Letters – general, 1999 (Box-folder 12/22)
        - Home Health Care, 1999 (Box-folder 12/23)
        - Medical Privacy Regulations, 2000 (Box-folder 12/24)
        - Medically Underserved Areas / Health Professional Shortage Areas, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 12/25)
        - Medicare Adjusted Average Per Capita Cost, 1999 (Box-folder 12/26)
        - Medicare Patient Choice and Access Act, 1997 (Box-folder 12/27)
        - Medicare Private Contracting, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 12/28)
        - Medicare Reform and Spending, 1997 (Box-folder 12/29)
        - Needle Exchange Programs, 1998 (Box-folder 12/30)
        - Older Americans Act, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 12/31)
        - Pap Screening (Medicare Reimbursement), 1999 (Box-folder 12/32)
        - Patient Access to Responsible Care Act, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 13/1 - 13/2)
        - Patient Protection Act (H.R. 4250) – Republican Health Plan, 1998 (Box-folder 13/3)
        - Patient Rights - Bilirakis Patient Protection Act (H.R. 448), 1999 (Box-folder 13/4)
        - Patient Rights – Employment Retirement Income Security Act, 1999 (Box-folder 13/5)
        - Patient Rights – Ganske Patient Right To Know Act, 1997 (Box-folder 13/6)
        - Patient Rights – Norwood-Dingell-Ganske Bipartisan bill, 1999 (Box-folder 13/7)
        - Social Security Facts, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 13/8)
        - Social Security Guarantee Plan (Archer/Shaw reform), 1999 (Box-folder 13/9)
        - Social Security Proposals, undated (Box-folder 13/10)
        - Social Security Revenue and Tax Code Reform, 1998 (Box-folder 13/11)
        - State Children’s Health Insurance Program, 1998 (Box-folder 13/12)
        - Teenage Detention, 2000 (Box-folder 13/13)
        - Welfare Reform Law, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 13/14)
      - Housing, 1994-1999
        Records document legislative responses to homelessness, and reflect Metcalf’s activities as a member and chair of the Republican Housing Opportunity Caucus (RHOC). In 1997, Metcalf introduced the Robert Stodola Homeless Veterans’ Assistance Act, requiring that McKinney Homeless Assistance Act programs devote 20% of funding to homeless veterans. He also sought to amendments to the Native American Housing Assistance and Self-Determination Act of 1996, and co-sponsored the Affordable Housing Barrier Removal bill of 1998. Metcalf’s activities as head of the RHOC included support of the low income housing tax credit to encourage private investment in affordable housing.
        - Affordable Housing Barrier Removal bill, 1998 (Box-folder 13/15)
        - Affordable Housing Improvement Act (H.R. 3290), 1998 (Box-folder 13/16)
        - Affordable Housing Tax Credit Award, circa 1997 (Box-folder 13/17)
        - Cascade Inter-Tribal Housing Authority, 1998 (Box-folder 13/18)
        - Derivatives, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 13/19)
        - Fair Housing Act amendment, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 13/20)
        - Federal Housing Authority – adjustable rate mortgages, 1998 (Box-folder 13/21)
        - Federal Housing Authority – loan limits, 1998 (Box-folder 13/22)
        - Homeless – Continuum of Care, 1998 (Box-folder 13/23)
        - Homeless Housing Programs Consolidation and Flexibility Act (H.R. 217)
          - Lazio Letter, 1998 (Box-folder 13/24)
          - Report language, 1997 (Box-folder 13/25)
          - Subcommittee Report, 1997 (Box-folder 13/26)
          - Testimonies to Subcommittee, 1997 (Box-folder 13/27)
        - Homeless Veterans Symposium, Everett Naval Station, 1998 April 17 (Box-folder 13/28 - 13/29)
        - Homeowners’ Disaster Insurance, 1997; 1999 (Box-folder 13/30)
        - Homeowners’ Insurance Availability Act (H.R. 21), 2000 (Box-folder 13/31)
        - Homeownership legislation, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 13/32)
        - Homeownership Symposium [June 24, 1997] (Box-folder 13/33)
        - Housing Appropriations, 2000 (Box-folder 13/34)
        - Housing Co-operatives, 1998 (Box-folder 13/35)
        - Housing letters, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 13/36)
        - Housing program funding FY 2000, circa 1999 (Box-folder 13/37)
        - Limited Partnership for Housing (Naval Station Everett, Washington), 1995-1997 (Box-folder 13/38)
        - Low Income Housing Tax Credit – correspondence, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 14/1)
        - Low Income Housing Tax Credit – housing credit data, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 14/2)
        - Low Income Housing Tax Credit – General Accounting Office report, 1997 (Box-folder 14/3 - 14/4)
        - Low Income Housing Tax Credit – letters of support, 1997 (Box-folder 14/5)
        - Low Income Housing Tax Credit – press conference program, 1998 May 7 (Box-folder 14/6)
        - Low Income Housing Tax Credit – supporting materials, circa 1995-1996 (Box-folder 14/7)
        - Manufactured Housing Program, circa 1997-1998 (Box-folder 14/8)
        - McKinney Homeless Assistance Act, 1997 (Box-folder 14/9)
        - McKinney Homeless Assistance grants – Lazio Amendments, 1999 (Box-folder 14/10)
        - Mortgage Interest Deductions, 1995; 1997 (Box-folder 14/11)
        - Native American Housing Assistance & Self-Determination Act amendments, 1996-1998 (Box-folder 14/12 - 14/14)
        - Private Mortgage Insurance, 1997 (Box-folder 14/15)
        - Real Estate Settlement Procedures Act, 1997 (Box-folder 14/16)
        - Republican Housing Opportunity Caucus (RHOC), Caucus Information, 1996; 1999 (Box-folder 14/17)
        - RHOC - Homeownership Task Force, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 14/18)
        - RHOC – Housing Organizations, 1997 (Box-folder 14/19)
        - RHOC – Housing Resolution (H.Con.Res. 208), 1998 (Box-folder 14/20)
        - RHOC – Low Income Housing Tax Credit, 1997-1999 (Box-folder 14/21 - 14/22)
        - RHOC - Meeting materials, February 11 Meeting, 1997 (Box-folder 14/23)
        - RHOC - Meeting materials, April 4th Meeting, 1997 (Box-folder 14/24)
        - RHOC - Meeting materials, April 8th Meeting, 1997 (Box-folder 14/25)
        - RHOC - Meeting materials, April 29th Meeting, 1997 (Box-folder 14/26 - 14/27)
        - RHOC - Meeting materials, March 17th Meeting, 1998 (Box-folder 14/28)
        - RHOC – Metcalf Statement to Committee on Oversight, 1997 May 1 (Box-folder 14/29)
        - RHOC - Photographs, undated (Box-folder 14/30)
        - RHOC - Press statement, 1996 September 26 (Box-folder 14/31)
        - Rural Housing, 1997 (Box-folder 14/32)
        - Section 8 Housing, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 14/33)
        - Senior Citizens’ Housing, 1999 (Box-folder 14/34)
        - Stodola Homeless Veterans Assistance Act (H.R. 1754) – bill drafts, 1997 (Box-folder 14/35)
        - Stodola Homeless Veterans Assistance Act (H.R. 1754) – correspondence, 1997 (Box-folder 14/36)
        - Stodola Homeless Veterans Assistance Act (H.R. 1754) – talking points, 1997 (Box-folder 14/37)
        - Stodola Homeless Veterans Assistance Act (H.R. 1754) – veterans’ support, 1997 (Box-folder 14/38)
        - Washington Housing Finance Commission, 1998 (Box-folder 14/39)
      - Immigration and Border Issues, 1995-2000
        A founder of the Northern Border Caucus, Metcalf supported increased staffing along the northern US Border and attempts to restrict legal immigration. He meanwhile opposed automated border entry and exit systems and the proposed introduction of border fees that might threaten the influx of trade and tourism to Washington State. Immigration and Border files reflect the tension between interests seeking to reduce the number of immigrants entering the US, and the desire of agricultural lobbyists including Washington farmers to protect access to temporary and seasonal alien workers.
        - Bipartisan Congressional Immigration Caucus, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 15/1)
        - Border Trade Alliance, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 15/2)
        - Chain Migration, 1999 (Box-folder 15/3)
        - Federation for American Immigration Reform (general information), undated (Box-folder 15/4)
        - H1-B “Quick Reference, 2000 (Box-folder 15/5)
        - H1-B legislation - American Business for Legal Immigration, 1998 (Box-folder 15/6)
        - H1-B program – opposition, 1999 (Box-folder 15/7)
        - H2-A Agricultural Guest Worker Program, 1998 (Box-folder 15/8)
        - H2-A Agricultural Guest Worker Program, circa 2000 (Box-folder 15/9)
        - Immigration Case Files, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 15/10 - 15/12)
        - Immigration Moratorium bill, 1995 (Box-folder 15/13)
        - Immigration Reorganization and Improvement Act, 1999 (Box-folder 15/14)
        - Immigration Review, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 15/15)
        - INS Border Patrol, 1997-2000 (Box-folder 15/16 - 15/18)
        - INS Immigration Information, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 15/19)
        - INS Travel Documents – Form I-68, 1995 (Box-folder 15/20)
        - Legal Immigration Report (Jordan Commission on Immigration Reform), 1995 (Box-folder 15/21)
        - National Tour Association – Immigration Reforms, 1999 (Box-folder 15/22)
        - Negative Population Growth, 1996-1999 (Box-folder 15/23)
        - Northern Border Agent Allocation, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 15/24)
        - Northern Border Caucus, undated; 1999 (Box-folder 15/25)
        - Population Resource Center, circa 1999 (Box-folder 15/26)
        - Private Immigration Bills, 1999 (Box-folder 15/27)
        - Section 110 Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigrant Responsibility Act, 1997-2000 (Box-folder 15/28 - 15/30)
        - Section 245(i) Immigration and Nationality Act, 1997 (Box-folder 15/31)
        - Smith Immigration Bill (H.R. 2202), 1995-1996 (Box-folder 15/32 - 15/33)
      - International Trade and Foreign Affairs, 1994-2000
        International Trade and Foreign Affairs records reflect Metcalf’s interests as a member of the House Subcommittee on Domestic and International Monetary policy. Materials reflect some significant developments in international relations during the late twentieth century, including the impact of U.S. membership in the World Trade Organization, and debates regarding establishment of Permanent Normal Trade Relations with the Peoples’ Republic of China.
        - Africa - trade legislation, 1999 (Box-folder 15/34)
        - American International Automobile Dealers Association, 1999 (Box-folder 15/35)
        - Columbia, 2000 (Box-folder 15/36)
        - Côte d'Ivoire (Ivory Coast), 1998-1999 (Box-folder 15/37)
        - Cuba, 1999 (Box-folder 15/38)
        - Debt Relief for Poverty Reduction Act (H.R. 1095), 1999 (Box-folder 15/39)
        - Egypt – religious persecution, 1999 (Box-folder 15/40)
        - El Salvador – Medical Supplies, 1999 (Box-folder 15/41)
        - Foreign Trade Zones Board, 1999 (Box-folder 15/42)
        - General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade (GATT) – Uruguay agreement, 1994; undated (Box-folder 15/43)
        - Heritage Foundation – Executive Memorandum, 1996 (Box-folder 15/44)
        - Import and Export statistics, 1995-1997 (Box-folder 15/45)
        - International Monetary Fund, 1997-1999 (Box-folder 16/1 - 16/2)
        - Iran, 1999 (Box-folder 16/3)
        - Kazakhstan, 1999; undated (Box-folder 16/4)
        - Korea, 1999 (Box-folder 16/5)
        - Overseas Private Investment Corporation (OPIC), 1999-2000 (Box-folder 16/6)
        - OPIC / Foreign Operations Appropriations FY2000, 1999 (Box-folder 16/7)
        - Panama Canal / National Security Center, 1995-2000 (Box-folder 16/8 - 16/9)
        - Panama – Drug Trafficking, 2000 (Box-folder 16/10)
        - Puerto Rico, circa 1998 (Box-folder 16/11)
        - Sanctions Reform Bill, 1999 (Box-folder 16/12)
        - Sierra Leone, 1999 (Box-folder 16/13)
        - Small Business and International Trade – report, 1999 (Box-folder 16/14)
        - Steel – Anti-dumping and Countervailing Duty Laws, 1999 (Box-folder 16/15)
        - Trade Deficit Review Commission, 1999 (Box-folder 16/16)
        - Trade Protectionism, 1996 (Box-folder 16/17)
        - United Nations dues, 1999 (Box-folder 16/18)
        - US Army School of the Americas, 1997-1999 (Box-folder 16/19 - 16/20)
        - US-China Relations, 1996 - 2000 (Box-folder 16/21 - 16/23)
        - Vietnam Jackson-Vanik Waiver (H.J. Res 58), 1999 (Box-folder 16/24)
        - Washington State economy and foreign trade, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 16/25)
        - World Trade Organization – Carousel Retaliation Act, 1999 (Box-folder 16/26)
        - World Trade Organization – China, 2000 (Box-folder 16/27)
        - World Trade Organization – Electronic Commerce, 1999 (Box-folder 16/28)
        - World Trade Organization – Ministerial Congressional Advisory Group, 1999 (Box-folder 16/29)
        - World Trade Organization – US Participation, 1999 (Box-folder 16/30)
        - World Trade Organization - US Sovereignty, 2000 (Box-folder 16/31)
        - World Trade Organization – US Withdrawal (H.J.Res.90), 2000 (Box-folder 16/32)
      - Judiciary, 1997-1999
        - Census, 1999 (Box-folder 17/1)
        - Civil Asset Forfeiture Reform Act (H.R. 1658), 1999 (Box-folder 17/2)
        - Civil Rights Act, 1997 (Box-folder 17/3)
        - Office of Justice Programs - Grants, 1999 (Box-folder 17/4)
        - Independent Counsel Reform, 1999 (Box-folder 17/5)
        - Information Collections - Access and Anti-Piracy measures, 1999 (Box-folder 17/6)
        - Legal Services Corporation, 1999 (Box-folder 17/7)
        - Lowey/Canady .08 Blood Alcohol Content Bill, 1999 (Box-folder 17/8)
        - Ninth Circuit Court of Appeals, 1999 (Box-folder 17/9)
        - Office of Justice Programs – Grants, 1999 (Box-folder 17/10)
        - Office of Special Counsel, 1999 (Box-folder 17/11)
        - "Partial Birth" Abortion, 1997 (Box-folder 17/12)
        - Religious Freedom Amendment (H.J. Res. 78), 1998 (Box-folder 17/13)
        - Religious Liberty Protection Act (H.R. 1691), 1999 (Box-folder 17/14)
        - Seattle Court House, 1999 (Box-folder 17/15)
        - Twenty-first Amendment Enforcement Act (H.R. 2031), 1999 (Box-folder 17/16)
      - Labor, 1993-2000
        - American Worker Project – Subcommittee on Oversight & Investigation Report, undated (Box-folder 17/17)
        - Davis-Bacon Act (prevailing wage law), 1993; 1995 (Box-folder 17/18)
        - Minimum Wage, 2000 (Box-folder 17/19)
      - Pipeline Files, 1998-2000
        Records comprise press clippings, correspondence, statements, hearings transcripts and reports documenting the aftermath of the June 10, 1999 gas pipeline explosion at Whatcom Creek in Bellingham, Washington. Materials include testimony heard by the House Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings, Hazardous Materials and Pipeline Transportation in October 1999, and by a Senate Field Hearing in March 2000. Files reflect subsequent attempts by community organizations such as SAFE Bellingham and Washington politicians including Metcalf to enact pipeline safety legislation.
        - House Subcommittee Hearings [October 27, 1999], 1999-2000 (Box-folder 17/20)
        - Hydrostatic Testing, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 17/21)
        - Industry approach to safety issues, 2000 (Box-folder 17/22)
        - Office of Inspector General report, 2000 (Box-folder 17/23)
        - Office of Pipeline Safety Corrective Action Order, 1999 (Box-folder 17/24)
        - Olympic Pipeline/Whatcom Creek Explosion, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 17/25 - 17/27)
        - Olympic Pipeline/Whatcom Creek Explosion – press clippings, 1998-2000 (Box-folder 17/28)
        - Olympic Pipeline/Whatcom Creek Explosion – press releases, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 17/29)
        - Pipeline Safety and Community Protection Act (Administration bill), 2000 (Box-folder 17/30)
        - Pipeline Safety bill (H.R. 3558), 2000 (Box-folder 17/31)
        - Pipeline Safety bill (Murray), 2000 (Box-folder 17/32)
        - Pipeline Safety bill (S. 2004)– Bricklin recommendations, 2000 (Box-folder 17/33)
        - Pipeline Safety legislation – Bill comparisons, 2000 (Box-folder 17/34)
        - Pipeline Safety legislation – Clean Water Act Model, 1999 (Box-folder 17/35)
        - Pipeline Safety legislation – McCain proposals, 2000 (Box-folder 17/36)
        - Pipeline Safety legislation - Oberstar bill, 2000 (Box-folder 17/37)
        - Senate Field Hearing, Bellingham City Hall, 2000 March 13 (Box-folder 17/38)
        - State and Federal Jurisdiction over Natural Gas Pipelines, 1998 (Box-folder 17/39)
        - Washington State recommendations, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 17/40)
      - Resources, 1992-2000; (bulk 1995-2000)
        Resources Files document ongoing conflicts regarding the management of national and regional resources including use of National Park and National Forest land, fish and water conservation, Army Corps of Engineers development projects, and the proposed environmental clean-up of “Superfund” sites. A significant amount of material pertains to the use of resources in Alaska and Washington State, with clean-up information pertaining to Washington locations including Bellingham Bay, the Tulalip Landfill in Marysville, and Hanford nuclear site. These records also contain general information regarding the provisions and implementation of Environmental Protection Agency programs, including allegations of the misuse of Superfund and proposals for the program’s reform. A member of the Committee on Science’s Subcommittee on Energy and the Environment, Metcalf supported a ban on Alaska North Slope Oil, co-sponsored the Puget Sound Ecosystem Restoration Initiative to conserve regional salmon stocks, and introduced a National Organic Program Clarification bill in 1998.
        - Air Pollution, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 18/1)
        - Alaska North Slope oil, 2000 (Box-folder 18/2)
        - American Heritage Rivers Initiative (AHRI), 1998 (Box-folder 18/3)
        - Arctic National Wildlife Refuge Drilling, 1995-1999 (Box-folder 18/4 - 18/5)
        - Arlecho Creek, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 18/6)
        - Army Corps of Engineers- Dams and Funding, 1998 (Box-folder 18/7)
        - Army Corps of Engineers – Mount St. Helens project, 1999 (Box-folder 18/8)
        - Army Corps of Engineers- Nooksack Flood, 1997 (Box-folder 18/9)
        - Army Corps of Engineers – Resources Investments Inc. Landfill Case, 1998 (Box-folder 18/10)
        - Bear Protection Act, 1997 (Box-folder 18/11)
        - Bellingham Bay Clean-up, 1999 (Box-folder 18/12)
        - Bonanza Queen Mine (Mt. Baker-Snoqualmie National Forest), 1999 (Box-folder 18/13)
        - Brownfield Economic Revitalization Act (HR 1049), 1997 (Box-folder 18/14)
        - Bureau of Land Management 1998 Budget Proposal, 1997 (Box-folder 18/15)
        - Canyon Lake Creek, 1998 (Box-folder 18/16)
        - Cedar River Habitat Conservation Plan, 1999 (Box-folder 18/17)
        - Children’s Environmental Protection and Right to Know Act (H.R. 1636), 1997 (Box-folder 18/18)
        - Chilean Salmon, 1997 (Box-folder 18/19)
        - Clean Congress Act, 1995 (Box-folder 18/20)
        - Clean Water legislation, 1996-1998 (Box-folder 18/21)
        - Co-Sponsored Bills/Responses, 1997 (Box-folder 18/22)
        - Commodities, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 18/23)
        - Constituent Form Letters, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 18/24)
        - Diesel Fuel Tax, 1995 (Box-folder 18/25)
        - District Issues, 1997 (Box-folder 18/26)
        - Ebey's Landing, 1997-1998; 2000 (Box-folder 18/27)
        - Elwha River, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 18/28)
        - Endangered Species Act – Background and implementation, circa 1997 (Box-folder 18/29)
        - Endangered Species Act – Private Property Rights, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 18/30)
        - Endangered Species Act – reform proposals, 1995-1997 (Box-folder 18/31)
        - Endangered Species Act – Tribal Rights, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 18/32)
        - Estuary Restoration Partnership Act, 1999 (Box-folder 18/33)
        - Fixed Anchors, 1998 (Box-folder 18/34)
        - Green Scissors report, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 18/35)
        - Hanford Reach Bill, 1997 (Box-folder 18/36)